MOAMEN MAMDOUH

Cairo - Egypt +20 111 0012 474 moamen.mamdouh1@gmail.com

LinkedIn · GitHub

A Senior testing engineer with 4 years of experience across different major software industries including e-commerce, telecommunications.

Always being a part of agile teams applying different agile approaches as scrum, kanban, and safe.

A key player in delivering top quality projects including Vodafone UK TOBi chatbot, noon's seller onboarding and preorders portals, and MD Labs ANDE project.

EXPERIENCE

FEB 2023 - PRESENT

SENIOR TESTING ENGINEER, VODAFONE INTELLIGENT SOLUTIONS

- Explicitly defined testing scope and exit criteria with project's stakeholders.
- Created test plans according to different projects' objectives.
- Analyzed test flows and scenarios, and designed test cases accordingly.
- Prepared test data to cover all designed test scenarios ensuring full test coverage.
- Created new test automation scripts and maintained already existing ones.
- Actively participated in agile team ceremonies and presented sprints' deliverables from testing perspective.

NOV 2020 - FEB 2023

SOFTWARE QUALITY ENGINEER, NOON

- Provided inputs on high-level test scenarios, challenges, risks, resources, and test estimates.
- Handled & tested different aspects of applications.
- Performed user interface, integration, regression, and smoke testing.
- Created test automation frameworks and executed testing scripts.
- Bug management and bug reporting.
- Coordinated with the engineers on result and defects status on regular basis.

NOV 2019 - NOV 2020

SOFTWARE QUALITY ENGINEER, MD LABS.

- Created user stories and test cases through analyzing business requirements.
- Designed and executed manual test cycles to cover project different scenarios.
- Created bug reports on Jira and produced test process reports using Qmetry.
- Applied performance testing using Jmeter.
- Gained test automation knowledge using Selenium, Maven, and TestNG.

JUL 2019 - NOV 2019

FREELANCE SOFTWARE TESTER, TESTER WORK

- Executed test Cases based on previously designed test Scenarios.
- Created bug reports and produced test process reports.

EDUCATION

JULY 2019

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER ENGINEERING, AIN SHAMS UNIVERSITY

Graduation Project

Students Affairs' chatbot using python framework "Rasa".

OCT 2019

CERTIFIED TESTER FOUNDATION LEVEL, ISTQB

International Software Testing Qualifications Board Foundation level certificate. *Credential ID* 191003033

SKILLS

MANUAL TESTING

- Test analysis and design (test plans, test cases)
- Test reporting and management using Jira, and Azure DevOps
- Test execution (regression, smoke, UAT)
- Agile testing (scrum, kanban, safe)

BACKEND TESTING

- Databases testing using SQL queries
- APIs testing using Postman

TEST AUTOMATION

 Creating test automation scripts in POM design pattern using Selenium, Maven, and TestNG Creating BDD automation scripts using Cucumber and Gherkin language

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- OOP using Java and C++ (LinkedIn verified)
- Web applications development using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Embedded Systems development using C (LinkedIn verified)
- Python programming
- Databases management using SQL
- Source control using Git

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Arabic Mother Tongue
- English Fluent

AWARDS

Dragon rank at test automation university

Test Automation University | Moamen-Mamdouh